Artifacts Register, 1879-[ongoing]
Smith College Archives
- Candle Holder/N.D., 162; 6" x 4" metal, glass
  Candle holder in shape of lantern with glass door. Featuring hand-painted designs. SC Relief Unit souvenir.
- Smith Pin/N.D., 163; 1/8" gold
  Rectangle with "Smith" across it; loop on bottom for pendant.
- SC Relief Unit Mug/1914, 164; 3.25" x 3" ceramic
  "1914" and various decoration. Souvenir.
  cracked
- SC Relief Unit Medal/c. 1915, 165; 2.25" x 2" metal
  Medal worn on uniform of Relief Unit? Shape of shield.
- no artifact, 166
- SCRU Medal/ c. 1920, 167; 1 0.75" across metal
  Medal features winged angel (Michael?) on front and names of Allied countries on reverse. On rainbow-striped ribbon. Ribbon bars read "St. Mihiel" and "Defensive Sector". See accompanying documentation.
- Typewriter Ribbon Tin/N.D., 168; 1 0.75" across metal
  Corona brand. Black. Significance unknown--perhaps a souvenir from SCRU.
  Discarded 8/2002.
- Mantle Mug/ N.D., 169; 8" x 5 0.75" china
  Blue and white mantle mug from home of L. Clark Seelye. See accompanying documentation.
  Broken, very fragile
- U.S. Bar Insignia Pins/ N.D., 170 a-e; 5/8" x 1.25" metal
  Five pins. One additional pin, missing its clasp, was discarded. This pin was identical to 170c.
- Coins/N.D., 171; 1", 1 3/16" metal
  Two coins-Belgian, Italian.
  not good
- Buttonhole Tack/N.D., 172; 11/16" x 1/8" metal
  Red, white, and blue bar. See accompanying documentation.
- Medals/N.D., 173
  Various (four) SCRU/WWI medals. Two on striped ribbons.
- Class Pin/1895, 174; 0.75" x.5" metal
  Green flag; "SC 95" inscribed.
- Class Pin/1896, 175; 0.75" x.5" metal
  White "S" entwined with "96".
- Class Pin/1897, 176; 0.75" x.5" metal
  White and gold; "S" entwined with "97".
- Class Pin/1898, 177; 1" x 9/16" metal
  Diamond shape; white, red, and gold. "SC" on top half; "98" on bottom.
- Class Pin/1899, 178; 0.75" x 5/8" metal
  "S" atop green and gold "99".
- Class Pin/1900, 179; 0.75" x.5" metal
  Oval with "S" and "1900" entwined.
- Class Pin/1901, 180; 5/8" x 3/8" metal
  Black/gold diamond shape, white/gold "1901".
- Class Pin/1902, 181; 5/8" x 5/16" metal
  "S" shape with "1902" in red.
- Class Pin/1903, 182; 5/8" x 5/8" metal
  Green "1903" on gold diamond shape.
- Class Pin/1904, 183; 0.5" across metal
  Purple and gold.
- Class Pin/1905, 184; 0.5" x.5" metal
  Entwined square "SC"; "1905" in center.
- Class Pin/1906, 185; 9/16" x.5" metal
  Snake "S" with red "06" overlaid.
- Class Pin/1906, 186; 0.5" x.5" metal
  Red/gold shield with "SC 1906".
- Class Pin/1907, 187; 0.5" x.5" metal
  Entwined "SC" and "07".
- Class Pin/1908, 188; 0.5" x 3/8" metal
  "SC" and "08".
- Class Pin/1909, 189; 3/8" x.5" metal
  "SC" and "09" in diamond-shape cutout.
- Class Pin/1910, 190; 5/8" x 5/16" metal
  Oval "SC" and "10".
- Class Pin/1911, 191; 0.5" x 3/8" metal
  "SC" and "11" cutout.
- Class Pin/1912, 192; 3/8" x.5" metal
  Rounded "SC" and "12" cutout.
- Class Pin/1913, 193; 0.5" x 3/8" metal
  Pyramid-shaped "SC" and "13" cutout.
- Class Pin/1914, 194; 5/8" x.5" metal
  Shield-shaped "SC" and "14" cutout.
- Class Pin/1915, 195; 0.25" x.5" metal
  Oval "SC" and "15" cutout.
- Class Pin/1916, 196; 5/8" x 3/8" metal
  Oval "SC", "19", and "16" cutout.
- Class Pin/1917, 197; 0.25" x.25" metal
  Block "SC" and "17" cutout.
- Class Pin/1918, 198; 0.5" acr. metal
  Round "SC" and "18" cutout.
- SC Spoon/N.D., 199; 6" silver
  JMG and College Hall depicted in bowl; SC seal on tip of handle. Fundraiser.
  tip of bowl damaged
- SC Spoon/N.D., 200; 5 0.75" silver
  College Hall depicted in bowl; words "Meadow City", SC seal, and Sophia Smith on handle. Fundraiser.
- SC Spoon/N.D., 201; 6.25" silver, enamel
  Plain bowl; white enamel handle with "SC" and motto in Greek. Fundraiser.
- SC Spoon/N.D., 202; 5 0.75" silver
  Plain bowl; "SC" on handle tip. Fundraiser.
- SC Spoon/N.D., 203; 5 0.75" silver
  College Hall depicted in bowl; detailed handle. Fundraiser.
- SC Spoon/N.D., 204; 6" silver
  Plain bowl; white "SC" and motto on handle. Fundraiser.
- SC Spoon/N.D., 205; 4.5" silver, enamel
  Plain bowl; "SC" in white enamel on handle. Fundraiser.
- SC Spoon/N.D., 206; 5 1/8" silver, enamel
  Interior of JMG depicted in bowl; "SC" in white enamel on handle tip. Fundraiser.
- SC Spoon/N.D., 207; 4.5" silver, enamel
  see description of #205
- SC Spoon/N.D., 208; 5.5" silver
  College Hall depicted in bowl; decorated handle with initial "B". Fundraiser.
- SC Spoon/N.D., 209; 4.5" silver
  Plain bowl; "SC" on handle. Similar to #s 205 and 207, w/out enamel. Fundraiser.
- Wrist Watch/ 1991, 210; 8.5" x 1" glass, vinyl or plastic, quartz
  Class of 1946 Reunion favor. White face with red outline of Dewey House; says "Smith College" at top and "1946" at bottom. Black watch band.
  Belonged to Eleanor Lincoln, who gave it to CA.
  91A-121
- Necklace/N.D., 211; 17" long metal, quartz
  Necklace once belonged to Sophia Smith. "Yellow metal" and quartz, ranging from smoky to citrine.
  Given by Mrs. Stafford E. Davis.
  91A- 259
- no artifact, 212
- SC Bicycle License Plates/ 1941-42, 1942-43, 213; painted metal
  #933 ('41-'42) and #845 ('42-'43).
  Given by Alice Ridenour Wareham 1944.
  92A- 82
- Plaque/N.D., 214; metal, wood
  Shovel, spray-painted gold, mounted on wood. Ceremonial shovel used for groundbreaking for library additions.
  From librarian's office.
  92A-148
- SC Medal/1984, 215; bronze
  Described under #39. Inscribed to Dorothy C. Goodwin 1937.
  UConn Homer Babbidge Library U-5A Storrs, CT 06269-1005 Deaccessioned from D.C. Goodwin papers. Rec'd by Sarah Pritchard.
  93A-8
- Small Basketball/1993, 216; 3" across rubber
  Souvenir from banquet celebrating women's basketball centennial, February 27, 1993. Blue and white. Mfd. by Spaulding.
  College archivist obtained at banquet.
- Pin/1992, 217; 7/8" x 7/8" Metal, enamel
  Made for women's basketball centennial celebrations, February 1992.
  From athletics dept.
- SC Plate/N.D., 218; 6" across china
  Round plate featuring College Hall in black with "Smith College, Northampton, Mass" beneath. Rimmed in gold. Reverse reads "Wm. Dearden Northampton, Mass".
  Given by Tammy Heller Greeman 1953.
  93A- 85
- Bicycle License Plates/1947-48, N.D., 219; 3" across 7" x 2.25" metal
  One round orange plate, #304, SC 1947-48. One oblong green plate, #6943, Northampton, N.D.
  Given by Margot (Lehman) Corneretto 1948.
  93A- 92
- Silver Cup/ N.D., 220; silver
  Base inscribed with "Edith Charters Gallagher '07"; body inscribed with names of rest of Class of 1907.
  From Circulation Dept. Browsing Room given in memory of ECG by her parents.
  93A- 115
- Silver Cup/ 1923, 221; silver
  Inscribed "To Smith College in greeting from Vienna, Austria, 1923, Noemi C. Vetter". Vetter gave a series of lectures at Smith on Austrian art.
  From Circulation Dept.
  93A-115
- SC Bicycle License Plate/ 1941-42, 222; 3" across painted metal
  Round; white with black letters.
  Given by Jean (Harriman) Porter 1944.
  93A- 147
- SC Basketball Centennial Paperweight/ 1992, 223; 2 0.75" acr. x 1" walnut, oak
  Women's Basketball Centennial and "Smith College 1892-1992". Made by Identification Systems, Inc. of Girard, PA. Laser carved.
  From College Relations.
  93A- 222
- Rubber Stamp/ 1989, 224; 4.25" x 3" wood, rubber, plastic
  Stamp reads "See Barbara Bush Make the Grade". Made by Pioneer Valley Stamp, Co. for college relations office for Convocation 1989 (Barbara Bush was speaking).
  94A-25
- SC Seal/N.D., 225; 16" x 16" wood, metal
  Seal mounted on wood in shape of a shield. See also Item #s 226 and 227.
- SC Seal/N.D., 226; 16" x 16" wood, metal
  Seal mounted on wood in shape of a shield. See also Item #s 225 and 227.
- SC Seal/N.D., 227; 10" x 11" wood, metal
  Seal mounted on wood in shape of a shield. Made by College Seal and Crest Co. See also Item #s 225 and 226.
  Belonged to Ardelia Hall 1922. Given by Nancy Kemper in July 1982.
- AASC Sash/ c. 1881, 228; 40" x 9.25" cloth
  Rectangular with pointed ends. Off-white with gold AASC Seal at either end.
  Belonged to Harriette Mandana Dunton 1881. Given by Woodstock Historical Society 26 Elm St. Woodstock, VT 05091
  94A-90
- Dessert Plate/N.D., 229; 6" across ceramic
  Depicts Alumnae Gym.
  94A-273
- SC Ring/ c. 1930, 230; 0.5" x 7/8" metal
  Octagonal face with raised SC Seal. Crest on reverse.
  Belonged to Alma Louise Dunning 1930. Given on ALD's behalf by Mrs. Rose Weaver, via the AASC.
  95A-16
- T-shirt/1995, 231; 29" long 34" wide Size L cotton
  Grecourt Review T-shirt. Front features photo of "Reading Club"; back reads "George Eliot Club, Smith College, 1881" and features a quote about the club from Mary Mather 1883.
  From Leslie Fields 1995.
  95A-50
- T-shirt/1995, 232; size L cotton
  Bridge Program t-shirt. Green with white print on back: "Bridge Program, 25, 1970-1995, Celebrating Women of Color at Smith College".
- Fluted Cup/ 1985, 233; 6.25" high 3 0.75" acr. at mouth 1 0.75" acr. at base clear plastic
  Mary Maples Dunn Inauguration Commemorative Cup. Base reads, "Smith College - Inauguration - Mary Maples Dunn - the eighth president - September 29, 1985" on one side and features a sunflower on the other.
  From Sherrill Redmon of the Sophia Smith Collection.
  95A-59
  a bit scratched
- SC Ring/ c. 1924, 234; 0.75" metal, stone
  Silver SC seal set into onyx, onyx set into gold ring.
  From estate of Julia Pierson 1924. Sent by William G. Vogt, Vogt Law Offices.
  95A-117
- SC Keychain/ N.D., 235; 2 7/8" long 1/8" medallion metal
  Medallion depicts the Grecourt Gates and College Hall on one side, "SC" on reverse. Box containing keychain inscribed "With gratitude from the Central Illinois Smith Club".
  See Item #234.
- Coaster/1964, 236; 4 0.75" across glass
  Purple hand-blown glass. Designed by Muriel Crosby Willett 1924. Presented to each member of the Class of 1924 attending their 40th Reunion by MCW and her husband, Henry.
  95A- 117
- T-shirt/1989, 237; size large cotton
  Blue with white design. Depicts a pile of papers with one last piece fluttering to the top of the pile (says "$152,000,000"). See accompanying documentation.
  From Jon Roche in Advancement Services.
  95A-152
- Pierce Hall Weathervane/ N.D., 238; 76 0.75" tall brass?
  Detailed with representations of tuning keys and bass clef, topped by pennant with G-clef finial. Removed during Pierce Hall renovations, summer 1995. See accompanying documentation for sketch.
  From Gary Hartwell and Rick Konopka of Physical Plant.
  95A-181
  badly rusted
- Pierce Hall Dome/N.D., 239; c. 63" tall metal
  Somewhat bell-shaped, 8-sided. Removed during Pierce Hall renovations, summer 1995. See accompanying documentation for sketch.
- SCRU Souvenir/ c. 1920, 240; 1.5" across metal
  Round, hollow object with "Gott Mit Uns" inscribed with crown and laurel branches. Use unknown.
  some corrosion
- Bridge Keychain/1995, 241; 1.5" across wood, metal
  Celebrating 25th Anniversary of the Bridge Program. "25th Anniversary 1970-1995" on one side; "Bridge Program Smith College" on reverse.
- Lunch Bag/ 1995, 242; 6.5" x 6.5" x 3.5" coated paper, acrylic handles
  White paper bag with braided handles. SC seal embossed in blue with "Vivat Academia" above and "Smith College" below. Given with box lunches at inauguration of Ruth J. Simmons as SC president, September 30, 1995.
  From Margery N. Sly, College Archivist.95A-221
- SC Ring/1931, 243; silver, stone
  Silver SC seal set into onyx, onyx set into ring. "Smith 1931" and "Tommy to Wolffie" engraved inside.
  Belonged to Louise Wolff Kahn 1931.
  95A-220
  seal somewhat worn
- SC Charm/1931, 244; 0.75" x.5" metal, stone
  Gold SC seal set into onyx. Octagonal.
  Belonged to Louse Wolff Kahn 1931.
  good
- SC Placemats/ N.D., 245; 12.5" x 17.5" cotton
  Cream design on gold background depicting Smith scenes. Fringed edges. Acc. to donor, made by Folly Cove Designers, Folly Cove, MA.
  Given by Barbara Barnitz Larsen 1954.
  95A-250
  somewhat faded
- SC Emblem/ N.D., 246; 3.5" x 2.5" felt
  White felt shield with gold embroidered "S". Possibly used on sports uniforms?
  Given by Meg Armstrong 1977.
  95A-246
  slightly discoloured at edge
- SC Banner/ 1903, 247; 21.25" l 10" to 7" w felt
  "Smith '03" in white letters, sewn onto pennant-shaped green background.
  See Item #246.
- SC Gold Key Guide Badge/ N.D., 248; 3.5" x 2.25" paper
  White badge with red printing. Picture of key with space for name of guide.
  Part of ephemera collection on Ellen R. Weiss, made in 1995 as a req. for American Studies 350A.
- Hoop and Stick/ N.D., 249; 3' x 3' wood
- SC Lunchbox/ 1913, 250; 10" x 5" metal
  Black.
- Elm Branch/ 1987, 251; 1' x 1' wood
  Section of a branch from the President's Elm, removed January 1987.
  From Dick Munson of Botanic Gardens.
- Bucket/1901, 252; 12" x 14" wood
  "1901" in green on bucket.
- College Hall Doorknob/N.D., 253; 3" x 3" wood, metal
  Doorknob and keyhole mounted on wood. Presented to Emma Proctor for 46 years of service to SC.
- Sampler/N.D., 254; 18" x 10" wood, glass, paper
  Wood-framed cross-stitch sampler with Sophia Smith's picture at the top. Two copies.
- Hockey Stick/ 1906, 255; 3' wood
  Name of Edith Furbush 1906 in black ink.
  Belonged to Edith Furbush 1906. Donated by her niece Hilda Bolster Mason 1942 in late 1970s--sent via JKC, via Caryl Newhof.
  91A-247
- Alice Figurine/ c. 1905, 256; 5" wood
  Figure of Alice from Lewis Carroll's Alice in Wonderland. On a wooden stand. Details burned into wood. At figure's feet is carved "'03-'05". On figure's back and on bottom of stand is carved "SR 1905".
  Sarah Tinsley Rees? Susan Miller Rambo? (Mascot of Haven House 1904 was White Rabbit.) ?
- Plaque/c. 1915, 257; 24" x 38" wood
  Reads "War Relief Antiques for the Smith College Unit in France". White background featuring American and French flags.
  From Helen Smith Fuller 1939, rec'd November 29, 1988.
  88A-248
- Lamp/N.D., 258; 13" x 13" plastic?
  Lamp that started 1975 fire in Neilson Library. Melted/disfigured.
  melted
- Plaque/1967, 259; 1" x 5" metal
  Plaque from picture of Grecourt Gates. Reads: "Chateau de Robecourt / Grecourt, France / Headquarters of Smith College Relief Unit 1917-1920 / Presented by the Unit in honor of its fiftieth anniversary / June 3, 1967".
- Basket/N.D., 260; 1" x 1" wicker, ribbon
  Woven basket with yellow ribbon reading, "Smith College '29, 'We are for less toil'". Basket is natural color on bottom, green around top, and has red handle.
- College Hall Clock Hands/ N.D., 261; wood
  Hands from clock on College Hall clock tower. Four large, four small hands. Painted black with white and gold-leaf accents. Includes three small pieces broken off hands, which are in location at right. Larger pieces are on top shelf, 31E.
  From Andy Anderson and Barbara Footman of Physical Plant when new hands installed on tower clock, fall 1995.95A-241
  weathered, paint patchy, pieces broken off
- Class of 1916 Reunion Sash/ N.D., 262; 80" x 1.25" 92" x 1.25" 40" x 1.25" 2 satin, 1 velvet
  Three purple cloth sashes worn by members of Class of 1916 at various reunions.
  Margaret Wallace.
  94A-30
  stained and pin-holed
- Makeup Compact/N.D., 263; 3" x 3" metal
  Goldtone, cover features "SC" in white inscribed in a diamond shape. Some powder still intact.
- Tote-bags/N.D., 264; 15" x 7 0.75" x 7.25" duck-cloth
  Beige drawstring bag in heavy cotton, "SC" outlined in gold paint on front. Carried in Ivy Day parades. Two.
  a bit stained
- College Hall Pediment/N.D., 265; 20" high concrete
  Conical. Removed from College Hall during renovations, Nov. 1995. Mended by Harold Anderson of Physical Plant (concrete patched and metal bar placed in core).
  Harold Anderson of Physical Plant.
  96A-13
  cracked; mended
- Miniature Heron Sculpture/N.D., 266; 3.5" x 7" bronze
  Sculpture by SC art professor Elliot Offner. Heron shown with wings outstretched. Identical to sculpture in Botanic Garden pool.
  From Marion Stoddard Fletcher 1933 via the Worcester Smith Club, Nov. 28, 1994.
  94A-256
- Class of 1934 Stamps/1934, 267 a&b; approx. 1.5" x 1.5" x 7/8" and 1" x 1" x 1" metal, wood
  Two stamps featuring leaping gazelle and the year. Metal stamp mounted with nails on wooden blocks. Red ink residue on stamps.
  Class of 1934-Pres. Mrs. Warren Cooke.
  94A-122
- T-shirt/1995, 268; size L cotton
  Presidential Search Ctte t-shirt. Grey with black SC seal and words "Presidential Search Committee: 'The Ruth Finders'".
  Board of Trustees?
  95A-47
- College Hall Window Latches/N.D., 269; latches: 2 0.75" x 2 0.75" mounts: 1 0.75" x 1 0.75" iron?
  Scribed metal latches and mounts (two each). Removed during College Hall renovations, fall 1995.
  From Gary Hartwell of Physical Plant.
  96A-21
- Phoebe Reese Lewis Pin/1996, 270; 2.25" acr. metal
  Round button, photo image of PRL 1951 in center. Perimeter white with black letters: "Chair Extraordinaire". Created for the retirement of PRL as Chair of the Board of Trustees of SC.
  From President's Office, March 13, 1996.
  96A-48
- Conference T-shirt/ March 1-2, 1996, 271; size L cotton
  From SC Women's Studies Dept. conference (Il)legitimate Knowledge: the Challenge of Interdisciplinarity. Front of white shirt features conference name, date, department, logo. Back features phrase "It's a disciplinary thing (you wouldn't understand it)".
  From Susan Van Dyne of Women's Studies Dept. via Sherrill Redmon of Sophia Smith Collection
  96A-50
- Sunglasses/ 1996, 272; plastic
  Black lenses, yellow frames. "Rally Day 1996" printed in black on left bow.
  96A-98
- Ada Comstock Program T-shirt/1994, 273; size M cotton
  Beige background with image of stained-glass SC seal on front. Back reads, "Knowledge is power: Virtue is an angel, but she is a blind one, and must ask of Knowledge to show her the pathway that leads to her goal. -Sophia Smith 1796-1870." Used as an AC Program fundraiser in 1994. Designed by Cathy Jackman AC '95; quote selected by Maureen Horkan AC '95.
  From Judy Owen AC.
  96A-77
- Keepsake Box/ 1996, 274; 2.5" across paper
  Given to attendees of the SC Libraries symposium "Books Illustrated: A Symposium Celebrating the Work of Ruth Mortimer" April 12-13, 1996. Small box covered with handmade paste paper. Inside lid is label with title and dates of symposium. Each box contains one origami crane and three haiku by Ruth Mortimer.
  96A-75
- SC Seal Stamp/ N.D., 275; 2.5" x 1.25" 2.5" x 1.5" metal
  Two metal strips, each with two images of SC seal.
  Sent anonymously to D. Vikre of NPRC.
  96A-99
- Sophia Smith Bicentennial T-shirt/1996, 276; size L cotton
  Beige shirt with black and red lettering. Image of Sophia's head and "Founder, Smith College, Sophia Smith Bicentennial, 1796-1996" on front. Add'l text on reverse. Designed by Sophia Smith Bicentennial Ctte. Used as Ada Comstock Program fundraiser.
  Ada Comstock Program via Marilyn Metzler, AC.
  96A-100
- SC T-shirt/1993, 277; size L cotton
  White shirt with black lettering: list of events from "Application" to "Reunion" on front; "Just Do It" and "Smith College" on reverse. 1996 Class T-shirt?
  Alison Wong, President, Class of 1996. Says it was class shirt since 1993.
  96A-101
- Class of 1996 First-year T-shirt/1992, 278; size L cotton
  Navy, long-sleeved with white lettering: "Where women's minds matter" atop a woman symbol on front; "Smith College Class of 1996" on reverse. Designed by Winter Miller 1995.
  Alison Wong, President, Class of 1996.
  spotted
- Class of 1996 Sports Bra/1996, 279; size M cotton, poly, spandex
  Black sports bra with blue lettering: "Smith supports women" on front. Used as a fundraiser by Class of 1996 sr. year.
- Class of 1996 Sports Bra/1996, 280; size S cotton, poly, spandex
  White sports bra with blue lettering: "Smith supports women" on front. Used as a fundraiser by Class of 1996 sr. year.
- Plate/1953, 281; 11" across silver
  "Henshaw Class of 1953" engraved in center; etched rim. Originally in Henshaw House when it was the Spanish-language house.
  Removed from Hatfield Hall storage. Given by Alice Clemente, Spanish/Portuguese Dept., via Beth Marshall, 5/10/96.
  96A-116
- Tankard/1961, 282; 4" high pewter
  Small tankard with handle. Engraved "In Memoriam 1958-1961".
  Hatfield Hall storage.
- Tea Urn/1961, 283; 16.5" high silver
  Engraved "Henshaw House". "1961" stamped on base. Contains spirit lamp to heat contents. Originally part of Henshaw House silver service. See Item #281.
  Hatfield Hall storage. From Alice Clemente, Spanish/Portuguese Dept., via Beth Marshall, 5/10/96.
- Plaque/N.D., 284; 9" x 15" brass?
  From steps between Morrow and Comstock Houses. Reads: "These steps are given in memory of Marian Ramsey Ewing 1883-1922 by the Class of 1905".
  96A-136
  slightly water-stained
- College Hall Turret Cap/N.D., 285; 5' tall copper
  Six-sided, conical base with pointed top. See accompanying documentation for sketch.
  From Gary Hartwell of Physical Plant. Removed during College Hall renovations, 1996.
  96A-76
  top is not attached to base
- Capital Campaign Banner/1984-89, 286; 7' 9 0.75" x 2' 10 0.75" felt
  Off-white with grey trim. Red letters reading "The Campaign for Smith". Used at 1984-89 CC events.
  Joyce Allen of the Development Office.
  96A-181
- Key Chain/1996, 287; 2.5" x 2" plastic, metal
  Sophia Smith Bicentennial key chain. Souvenir from SSB Symposium September 27-28, 1996.
- Preludes T-shirt/1994, 288; XL cloth
  Tie-dye design with "Smith College Preludes" written in black.
  Marshall Schalk's office.
- Lawrence House T-shirt/ c. 1992, 289; XL cloth
  Reads "Top Ten Reasons Lawrence House is cooler than yours". (#10 is "We have Marshall [Schalk]".)
- Mug/c. 1995, 290
  Total Quality Management souvenir given to Physical Plant workers, c. 1995.
  97A-46
- Pub Crawl T-shirt/1996, 291
  Class of 1996 Senior Pub Crawl T-shirt. Reads "The Evolution of a Senior".
  96A-207
- Sophia Smith Associates Centennial Pin/ 1975, 292; 2"x1.25" metal
  AASC. Pin is gold and in the shape of a cicada. See Item #12.
  Given by Louisa Shire Nathan 1941. Belonged to her aunt, A. Becker, of Chicago.
  97A-54
- Wedgwood Plate/1956, 293; 10.5" acr. china
  Depicting College Hall/Grecourt Gates in green in center of plate; cream border with raised pattern.
  From Clarence Darrow Octagon House, Kinsman, OH. Given to Darrow House by Eleanor Brown, niece of Helen Cobb 1916.
  97A-95
- SC Bottle of Water/c. 1997, 294; 22 cm. plastic, water
  16.9 oz. bottle of water with SC label. Distributed during 1997 Commencement wknd and for sale on campus thereafter.
  Sherrill Redmon of Sophia Smith Coll.
  97A-69
- Collapsible Seats/N.D., 295; 34" x 9" wood
  Yellow collapsible seats which, when folded, serve as canes. "1901" printed on seat. Used at unspecified reunion.
  Peg Pitzer of Advancement.
  97A-73
- Dining Services Patch/N.D., 296
  Arrived with various publications. ?
  97A-38
- Plaque/1996, 297; 4" x 6" wood, metal
  Reads "Office of Minority Affairs Presents to Ann Moss Burger, Dean of Smith College-In appreciation for her support of multicultural programs at SC, Northampton, MA, 1990-1996.
  From Dean of College's Office. Separated from larger accession.
  96A-157
- Sophia Smith Collection T-shirt/1992, 298; size M cotton
  White, short-sleeved. On front: suffragist propaganda picture of woman climbing ladder. On reverse: "Revealing Life Stories: the First Fifty Years of the Sophia Smith Collection 1942-1992".
  97A-152
- HONS T-shirt/N.D., 299; size XL cotton
  Head of New Students T-shirt. Blue, short-sleeved. On front: "Here to Help" in English, ASL, Thai, Spanish, German, and Russian. On reverse: "HONS (Heads of New Students) Smith College".
  Student Affairs.
- Preludes Banner/N.D., 300; cotton sheet
  Reads "Preludes: If you follow the rules, you miss all the fun". Covered with handprints. Possibly 1995.
  photo taken; discarded